<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Life Share</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Android Studio</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">android.studio@android.com</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="menu_home">Home</string>
    <string name="menu_gallery">Gallery</string>
    <string name="menu_slideshow">Slideshow</string>

    <string name="home_second">Home Second</string>
    <string name="quote">Blood donation is the real act of humanity</string>
    <string name="Signup">Sign Up</string>
    <string name="sign_in">Sign In</string>
    <string name="username_hint">Username</string>
    <string name="Passsword_hint">Password</string>
    <string name="register_btn_txt">Register</string>
    <string name="lifeshare_icon_img">lifeShare Icon</string>
    <string name="login_register_btn_txt">Login/Register</string>
    <string name="Firstname_txt">First Name</string>
    <string name="Lastname_txt">Last Name</string>
    <string name="Dob_txt">Date Of Birth</string>
    <string name="Gender_txt">Gender</string>
    <string name="male_txt">Male</string>
    <string name="female_txt">Female</string>
    <string name="others_txt">Others</string>
    <string name="Phone_txt">Phone no.</string>
    <string name="Email_txt">Email</string>
    <string name="Address_txt">Address</string>
    <string name="Username_txt">Username</string>
    <string name="password_txt">Password</string>
    <string name="ConfirmPassword_txt">Confirm Password</string>
    <string name="requirements_by_donation_type">Requirements by Donation Type</string>
    <string name="info_qoute">To ensure the safety of both patients and donors, these are some of the requirements donors must meet to be eligible to donate blood based on their donation type.</string>
    <string name="common_reason">Common Reasons People Can\'t Donate !</string>
    <string name="cold_heading">Cold, Flu and Other Types of Illness</string>
    <string name="cold_info">If you don’t feel well on the day of your donation, please call to cancel. We’ll be happy to see you 24 hours after your symptoms pass.</string>
    <string name="med_heading">Information About Medications</string>
    <string name="med_info">Most medications will not disqualify you from being able to donate blood, but may require a waiting period after your final dose.</string>
    <string name="iron_heading">Low Iron</string>
    <string name="iron_info">If you were unable to donate due to low iron, you may still be able to donate in the future. We recommends taking steps to help increase your iron level.</string>
    <string name="travel_heading">Travel Outside of the India</string>
    <string name="traveling_info">You may be deferred from donating blood or platelets if you have lived in or traveled to a malaria-risk country in the past three years.</string>
    <string name="whole_blood_heading">Whole Blood Donation</string>
    <string name="whole_blood_info">“Whole blood” is simply the blood that flows through your veins. It contains red cells, white cells, and platelets, suspended in plasma. \n• Donation frequency: Every 56 days* \n• You must be in good health and feeling well** \n• You must be at least 16 years old in most states \n• You must weigh at least 110 lbs</string>
    <string name="power_red_heading">Power Red Donation</string>
    <string name="power_red_info">Power Red is similar to a whole blood donation, except a special machine is used to allow you to safely donate two units of red blood cells during one donation while returning your plasma and platelets to you. \n• Donation frequency: Every 112 days, up to 3 times/year* \n• You must be in good health and feeling well** \n• Male donors+ must be at least 17 years old in most states, at least 5.1ft tall and weigh at least 130 lbs \n• Female donors+ must be at least 19 years old, at least 5.5ft tall and weigh at least 150 lbs</string>
    <string name="platelete_heading">Platelet Donation</string>
    <string name="platelete_info">Platelets are tiny cells in your blood that form clots and stop bleeding. For millions of Americans, they are essential to surviving and fighting cancer, chronic diseases, and traumatic injuries. Every 15 seconds someone needs platelets. Platelets must be used within five days and new donors are needed every day.
       \n •	Donation frequency: Every 7 days, up to 24 times/year*
    \n•	You must be in good health and feeling well**
    \n•	You must be at least 17 years old in most states
    \n•	You must weigh at least 110 lbs</string>
    <string name="elite_heading">AB Elite Plasma Donation</string>
    <string name="elite_info">During a plasma-only donation, blood is drawn from one arm and sent through a high-tech machine that collects your plasma and then safely and comfortably returns your red cells and platelets back to you, along with some saline. It takes only a few minutes longer than donating blood but can have a profound impact.
    Donors with type AB blood make ideal candidates for AB Elite plasma or platelet donations.

    \n•	Donation frequency: Every 28 days, up to 13 times/year*
    \n•	You must have type AB blood
    \n•	You must be in good health and feeling well**
    \n•	You must be at least 17 years old
    \n•	You must weigh at least 110 lbs</string>
    <string name="process">How does the blood donation process work?</string>
    <string name="process_info">Donating blood is a simple thing to do, but can make a big difference in the lives of others.
        The donation process from the time you arrive until the time you leave takes about an hour.
        The donation itself is only about 8-10 minutes on average. The steps in the process are:
\n
        \n   REGISTERATION
\n1.	You will complete donor registration, which includes information such as your name, address, phone number, and donor identification number (if you have one).
\n2.	You will be asked to show a donor card, driver’s license or two other forms of ID.
\n
        \n   HEALTH HISTORY AND MINI PHYSICAL
\n1.	You will answer some questions during a private and confidential interview about your health history and the places you have traveled.
\n2.	You will have your temperature, hemoglobin, blood pressure and pulse checked.
\n
        \n   DONATION
\n1.	We will cleanse an area on your arm and insert a brand–new, sterile needle for the blood draw. This feels like a quick pinch and is over in seconds.
\n2.	You will have some time to relax while the bag is filling. (For a whole blood donation, it is about 8-10 minutes. If you are donating platelets, red cells or plasma by apheresis the collection can take up to 2 hours.)
\n3.	When approximately a pint of blood has been collected, the donation is complete and a staff person will place a bandage on your arm.
\n
        \n   REFRESHMENTS
\n1.	You will spend a few minutes enjoying refreshments to allow your body time to adjust to the slight decrease in fluid volume.
\n2.	After 10-15 minutes you can then leave the donation site and continue with your normal daily activities.
\n3.	Enjoy the feeling of accomplishment knowing that you have helped to save lives.
\nYour gift of blood may help up to three people. Donated red blood cells do not last forever. They have a shelf-life of up to 42 days.
        A healthy donor may donate every 56 days.</string>
    <string name="after_donating">What should I do after donating blood?</string>
    <string name="after_donating_info">After you give blood:
\nTake the following precautions:
\n1.Drink an extra four glasses (eight ounces each) of non-alcoholic liquids.
\n2.Keep your bandage on and dry for the next five hours, and do not do heavy exercising or lifting.
\n3.If the needle site starts to bleed, raise your arm straight up and press on the site until the bleeding stops.
\n4.Because you could experience dizziness or loss of strength, use caution if you plan to do anything that could put you or others at risk of harm.
        \n5.For any hazardous occupation or hobby, follow applicable safety recommendations regarding your return to these activities following a blood donation.
\n6.Eat healthy meals and consider adding iron-rich foods to your regular diet, or discuss taking an iron supplement with your health care provider, to replace the iron lost with blood donation.
\n7.If you get a bruise:  Apply ice to the area intermittently for 10-15 minutes during the first 24 hours.
        Thereafter, apply warm, moist heat to the area intermittently for 10-15 minutes. A rainbow of colors may occur for about 10 days.
\n8.If you get dizzy or lightheaded:  Stop what you are doing, lie down, and raise your feet until the feeling passes and you feel well enough to safely resume activities.
\nAnd remember to enjoy the feeling of knowing you have helped save lives!</string>
    <string name="hurt">Will it hurt when you insert the needle?</string>
    <string name="hurt_info">Only for a moment. Pinch the fleshy, soft underside of your arm.
        That pinch is similar to what you will feel when the needle is inserted.</string>
    <string name="time">How long does a blood donation take?</string>
    <string name="time_info">The entire process takes about one hour and 15 minutes; the actual donation of a pint of whole blood unit takes
        8 to 10 minutes. However, the time varies slightly with each person depending on several factors including the
        donor’s health history and attendance at the blood drive.</string>
    <string name="often">How often can I donate blood?</string>
    <string name="often_info">You must wait at least eight weeks (56 days) between donations of whole blood and 16 weeks (112 days) between Power Red donations.
        Platelet apheresis donors may give every 7 days up to 24 times per year.
        Regulations are different for those giving blood for themselves (autologous donors).</string>
    <string name="who_can">Who can donate blood?</string>
    <string name="who_can_info">In most states, donors must be age 17 or older.
        Some states allow donation by 16-year-olds with a signed parental consent form.
        Donors must weigh at least 110 pounds and be in good health. Additional eligibility criteria apply.</string>
    <string name="eligibility">ELIGIBILITY:</string>
    <string name="eligibility_info">Eligibility for donating blood is as follows:
        \n1.Age should be between 18 and 60 years.
        \n2.You should not be suffering, or had history of cancer.
        \n3.You should not be suffering from any blood clotting disorder, such as haemophilia.
        \n
        \nIf you are eligible, you may register as a blood donor, but at the time of donating blood, follow the instructions mentioned below:
        \n1.Your weight should be 45kg or above
        \n2.Minimum haemoglobin count should be 12.5gm.
        \n3.Pulse rate should be between 50 and 100 per minute, without any irregularities.
        \n4.Blood pressure should be, diastolic 50 to 100 mm Hg and Systolic 100 to 180 mm Hg.
        \n5.Body temperature should be normal and oral temperature should not exceed 37.5 degree Celsius.
        \n6.Should not have undergone any treatment for rabies or received Hepatitis B immune globulin within the past one year.
        \n7.Should not have donated blood within last three months.
        \n8.Should not have been treated for malaria within last three months.
        \n9.Should not have undergone any immunization within the past one month.
        \n10.Should not have undergone any dental work or taken aspirin within last the 72 hours.
        \n11.Should not have consumed alcohol within the last 9 hours.
        \n12.If you have any chronic disease that is not mentioned here, you may register, but please inform the patient or the doctor or the hospital staff before you donate blood.
        \n
        \nPlease do not register as a blood donor or donate blood in case
        \n1.You are HIV+.
        \n2.You are suffering, or had history of cancer.
        \n3.You are suffering from any blood clotting disorder, such as haemophilia.</string>

    <!--donor msg-->
    <string name="msg1"> I am a rare blood Type (B-). This is what encouraged me to donate.with knowing I’m helping someone with an uncommon blood type is the reason I’ll be donating again in September.
Please donate blood , you’ll feel silly for avoiding it if you were afraid in the first place !</string>
    <string name="msg2">Its just a feeling of doing good for the world.
The blood we donate is going to help someone in need now or in the future so doing such a good deed feels fulfilling and happy at the same time </string>
    <string name="msg3">I felt good emotionally after donating blood because i know i have helped someone else who may be ill. </string>
    <string name="msg5">After donating blood i really felt like that I have made a contribution to the world. Some really needy people may have blood to live again. </string>
    <string name="msg4">I am happy and excited to donate my blood. :) hope we all would donate it in the future... "Donate Krke dkho,acha lagta h! </string>
    <string name="donor1">MOHSIN PATHAN</string>
    <string name="donor2">ZAID SHAIKH</string>
    <string name="donor3">AISHAH ANSARI</string>
    <string name="donor4">SHADAB ANSARI</string>
    <string name="donor5">SADIQ SONALKAR</string>


    <!--otp screen-->
    <string name="otp_code_text">co\nde</string>
    <string name="otp_verification_text">verification</string>
    <string name="otp_description_text">Enter one time password sent on </string>
    <string name="verify_code">VERIFY CODE</string>
    <string name="forget_password_detail">Provide Your Account\'s e-mail for which you want to change to reset your password </string>
    <string name="remember_me">Remember Me</string>
    <string name="forget_password">Forget Password</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="new_credential">New Credential</string>
    <string name="new_password_msg">Your identity have been verified! \nSet your new password</string>
    <string name="password_updated">Password Updated</string>
    <string name="your_password_has_been_updated">your password has been updated</string>
    <string name="blood_group">Blood Group</string>

    <string-array name="bloodgroup">
        <item>A+</item>
        <item>A-</item>
        <item>B+</item>
        <item>B-</item>
        <item>AB+</item>
        <item>AB-</item>
        <item>O+</item>
        <item>O-</item>
    </string-array>


</resources>